<input>

# Number of models for which details are described in this input file
<modelnumber> 1 </modelnumber>

# Restart from previous (pickled) population?
<restart> False </restart>

# Series of epsilons. (Whitespace delimited list)
# Multiple epsilon schedules can be specified by giving additional vectors enclosed in <e2> </e2>, <e3> </e3> etc
# NOTE: the parser always reads them in order and ignores the tag value
<epsilon> 
 <e1> 160 150 140 130 120 100 80 50 40 37 35 </e1>
</epsilon>

# Population size
<particles> 100 </particles>

# Beta is the number of times to simulate each sampled parameter set.
# This is only applicable for models simulated using Gillespie and SDE
<beta> 1 </beta>

# Internal timestep for solver.
# Make this small for a stiff model.
<dt> 1 </dt>


<data>
 # times: For ABC SMC, times must be a whitespace delimited list
 # In simulation mode these are the timepoints for which the simulations will be output
 <times> 0.0 0.6 4.2 6.2 8.6 13.4 16 21.4 27.6 34.4 39.8 40.6 45.2 </times>

 # variables: For ABC SMC, whitespace delimited lists of concentrations (ODE or SDE) or molecule numbers (Gillespie)
 # Denote your data via tags <v1> </v1> or <var1> </var1> or <v2> </v2> etc. The tags are ignored and the data read in order
 # For simulation these data are ignored
 # See fitting instruction below if the dimensionality of your data sets differ from the dimensionality of your model
 <variables>
 <var1> 0 2.04 32.29 4.13 2.15 5.09 1.07 3.67 39.01 73.83 8.54 17.62 11.96 </var1>
 <var2> 0 28.99 32.29 10.61 55.27 9.49 68.56 10.62 -1.95 3.53 63.87 39.68 -0.6 </var2>
 <var3> 0 20.96 7.49 44.25 7.12 60.52 8.10 63.76 22.9 6.27 10.59 6.50 70.56 </var3>
 </variables>
</data>

<models>
<model1>
<name> repressilator </name>
<source> repressilator.xml </source>

# type: the method used to simulate your model. ODE, SDE or Gillespie.
<type> ODE </type>

# Fitting information. If fit is None, all species in the model are fitted to the data in the order they are listed in the model.
# Otherwise, give a whitespace delimited list of fitting instrictions the same length as the dimensions of your data.
# Use speciesN to denote the Nth species in your model. Simple arithmetic operations can be performed on the species from your model.
# For example, to fit the sum of the first two species in your model to your first variable, write fit: species1+species2
<fit> species1 species3 species5 </fit>

# Priors on initial conditions and parameters:
# one of 
#       constant, value 
#       normal, mean, variance 
#       uniform, lower, upper 
#       lognormal, mean, variance 

<initial>
 <ic1> constant 0.0 </ic1>
 <ic2> constant 2.0 </ic2>
 <ic3> constant 0.0 </ic3>
 <ic4> constant 1.0 </ic4>
 <ic5> constant 0.0 </ic5>
 <ic6> constant 3.0 </ic6>
</initial>


<parameters>
<parameter1> constant 1 </parameter1>
<parameter2> uniform -2 10 </parameter2>
<parameter3> uniform  0 10 </parameter3>
<parameter4> uniform -5 20 </parameter4>
<parameter5> uniform 500 2500 </parameter5>
<parameter6> constant 1 </parameter6>
</parameters>
</model1>
</models>

</input>