<input>

# Number of models for which details are described in this input file
<modelnumber> 
  1
</modelnumber>

# Restart from previous (pickled) population?
<restart> 
  False
</restart>

# Series of epsilons. (Comma-delimited list)
# If the length of the epsilon series is one and you have only one model
# you are effectively doing abc Rejection

<epsilon> 
  <e1>
    5.0 4.0 3.0 
  </e1>
</epsilon>

# Number of particles
<particles>
  500
</particles>

# Beta is the number of times to simulate each sampled parameter set.
# This is only applicable for models simulated using SDE and Gillespie.
<beta>
  1 
</beta>

# Internal timestep for solvers
<dt> 
  0.01 
</dt>

# Type of kernels to use (default uniform)
<kernel>
  uniform
</kernel>

# Model perturbation kernel  (default 0.7)
<modelkernel>
  0.7
</modelkernel>

# Model prior (default uniform over models)
<modelprior>
  1.0
</modelprior>

<data>
  # times: For abc-SMC, times must be a whitespace delimited list starting with 0.
  # For simulation only the first and last timepoints are used.
  # To make a synthetic data set give a comma-delimited list of timepoints at which data points are required.

  <times>
    0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 
  </times>

  # variables: For abc-SMC, whitespace delimited lists of concentrations (ODE or SDE) or molecule numbers (Gillespie).
  # You can denote the names of the variables to be anything although they will labeled internally in order ie variable1, variable2, ..., variableN.
  # For simulation or synthetic data sets these data are ignored.
  # See fitting instruction below if the dimensionality of your data sets differ from the dimensionality of your model.

  <variables>
    <v1>
      2.0 6.95179937 8.56370876 8.98447127 9.83093446 9.62018385 9.62319942 10.04279309 9.97753801 9.70874283 10.0961697 
    </v1>    
</variables>
</data>

<models>
  <model1>
    <name>
      LinearGrowthModelModified 
    </name>
    
    <source>
      model_lingrow.xml 
    </source>
    
    # type: the method used to simulate your model. ODE, SDE or Gillespie.
    
    <type>
      SDE
    </type>

    # Fitting information. If fit is None, all species in the model are fitted to the data in the order they are listed in the model.
    # Otherwise, give a comma-delimited list of fitting instrictions the same length as the dimensions of your data.
    # Use speciesN to denote the Nth species in your model. Simple arithmatic operations can be performed on the species from your model.
    # For example, to fit the sum of the first two species in your model to your first variable, write fit: species1+species2

    <fit>
      None
    </fit>
    
    # Priors:
    # one of
    #       constant, value
    #       uniform, lower, upper
    #       normal, mean, sigma
    #       lognormal, location, scale

    <parameters>
      
      <parameter1>
	constant 1.0
      </parameter1>
      
      <parameter2>
	uniform 0 50
      </parameter2>
      
      <parameter3>
	uniform 0 5
      </parameter3>

    </parameters>

    <initial>
      
      <ic1>
	uniform 0 5.0
      </ic1>
   
    </initial>


  </model1>

</models>

</input>
